A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مذنّب لامع
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts tired by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's case is a "traverse"!
!"قضيّة اليوم عن "تسلّق جبال
Look it up and you'll find a zigzag hike!
!ارجع للقاموس وسترى صعود جبال متعرّج
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Bus Accident! Kindergartener Killed! CEO Murdered!!
!حادث حافلة! موت طالبة روضة !مقتل رئيس شركة تنفيذي
The CEO of a quick-loan company was murdered,
،قُتل الرئيس التنفيذي لشركة إقراض عاجل
and one child perished when a school bus was caught in the accident.
وتُوفيت طفلة عندما علقت حافلة مدرسية في الحادث
The man who ordered the murder has been arrested!
تمّ اعتقال الرجل الذي !طلب عملية القتل
He appears to have had a debt-related grudge.
يبدو أنّه كان يكنّ ضغينةً بسبب الديون
The murder was done by an unknown pro hitman known as the "Fox."
كان مُنفّذ الجريمة هو قاتل مأجور مجهول الهويّة يُدعى الثعلب
Investigations have been futile, and his whereabouts are unknown.
لم تثمر التحقيقات، ويبقى مكانه مجهولاً
I'm at the scene of the kindergartener's death six months ago.
أنا في موقع الحادث الذي تُوفيت فيه طفلة الروضة قبل 6 أشهر
The man responsible, the "Fox," is still at large, and the police--
...لا يزال الفاعل الثعلب طليقاً، والشرطة
Dad. You have a client.
أبي، لديك عميل
Client!
!عميل
Shut up... Don't yell...
اصمتي... لا تصرخي
He's already here.
لقد دخل بالفعل
Sorry for showing up so suddenly.
أعتذر على الظهور فجأةً
Not at all...
...لا مشكلة
F-Find the hitman and keep him from killing?!
أ-أجد القاتل المأجور !وأردعه عن القتل؟
I may not look it,
،قد لا يظهر ذلك عليّ
but I'm president of a Kansai real estate agency branch.
لكنّي رئيس فرع وكالة عقارات في كانساي
Ushio Bunzo (40) Real Estate Branch President
(أوشيو بونزو (40 رئيس فرع لوكالة عقارات
When I underwent the company's
عندما خضتُ الفحص الطبّي
health check five days ago,
للشركة قبل خمسة أيام
they mistook a simple ulcer for stomach cancer!
أخطؤوا باعتقاد أنّ محض قرحة !كانت سرطان معدة
I overheard the doctor and nurse,
سمعتُ كلام الطبيب والممرضة
so I was really shocked when I heard it was cancer!
!وصُدمت كثيراً عندما قالا أنّه سرطان
So don't tell me you... hired a hitman to kill you?
أيمكن أنّك عيّنت قاتلاً مأجوراً لقتلك؟
Yes. The Fox.
أجل، الثعلب
Fox?!
!الثعلب؟
But I only realized the mistake after I used my various work contacts
لكنّي أدركت الخطأ بعدما استعملت علاقاتي الواسعة في العمل
to get in touch with him.
للتواصل معه
My money transfer had been deposited,
كان تحويل المال قد تمّ
and his always-changing internet addresses had been closed out.
وعناوين الإنترنت التي يستعملها للتواصل قد أُغلقت
Even if I could contact him, it wouldn't be until a month later--
حتّى لو استطعتُ التواصل معه، فسيكون ذلك بعد شهر
basically, I can't contact him while he's out to kill me!
أي لا أستطيع الوصول له !بينما يسعى لقتلي
I see. So that's why you came to the great Mori Kogoro.
فهمت، لذا لجأتَ للمتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
But are you being serious?
لكن أأنت جاد؟
This isn't some hidden camera thing, is it?
لا توجد كاميرا مخفيّة في الجوار، صحيح؟
What?! Are you saying you can't trust me?!
!أيّها المتحرّي! أتقصد أنّك لا تستطيع الوثوق بي؟
No, I do!
!أجل... لا
Look out!
!انتبه
Bullets! Stay down!
!رصاصات! انخفضوا
That damn Fox...
...ذاك الثعلب الوغد
Damn! He got away!
تبّاً! هرب؟
It looks safe now.
يبدو أنّ الوضع بخيرٍ الآن
Oh, man...
...يا إلهي
Oh! What a big wallet! What's this?
محفظة كبيرة! ما هذا؟
It's nothing!
!لا شيء
What was that?
ما كان ذلك؟
Damn. We gotta call the police.
هذا سيّئ، لنتّصل بالشرطة بأيّ حال
No!
!كلا
I hired a killer to kill me!
!قد أكون الهدف، لكنّي من عيّن القاتل
No police!
!لن نلجأ للشرطة
Please! I beg you! I'll even pay for your windows!
!أرجوك! سأدفع تكاليف إصلاح النافذة
Yeah, okay. I'll take the case.
لا بأس، سأقبل القضيّة
Really, detective?!
!حقّاً أيّها المتحرّي؟
Allow the great Mori Kogoro to catch the deadly Fox
سيمسك المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو بالثعلب المميت
that's given the police so much trouble!
!الذي سبّب الكثير من العناء للشرطة
Great!
!رائع
Whoa, are you sure about this?
هل سيكون هذا بخير؟
But how are you gonna catch the Fox?
لكن كيف ستمسك بالثعلب؟
You don't know what he's like, right?
لا تعرف كيف يبدو، صحيح؟
Don't worry about that!
لا قلق حيال ذلك
The truth is, I included a condition with it!
في الواقع، ألزمتُ الثعلب بشرط
I asked him to kill me while I'm on one of my beloved traverse trips!
طلبت منه قتلي بينما أنا في إحدى رحلات تسلّقي للجبال التي أهواها
Traverse?
تسلّق الجبال؟
You mean like a trek up a mountain ridge?
أتقصد حيث تمشي على حافة الجبال؟
If it's to be during a traverse, then what was that attack just now?!
،إذا كان قتله أثناء تسلّق الجبال شرطاً فما كان هذا الهجوم؟
It's dangerous by the window. Let's talk over here.
المكان خطر قرب النافذة، لنتكلّم هنا
R-Right.
حسناً
There's definitely something more to this guy...
...يخفي هذا الرجل شيئاً
Tanbara Mountains
جبال تانبارا
The next day, we set out on a traverse up the Tanbara Mountain ridge.
في اليوم التالي، ذهبنا في رحلة تسلّق لسلسلة جبال تانبارا
This feels great!
!شعورٌ جميل
Take a picture, Conan-kun!
!التقط صورةً يا كونان-كن
We're gonna run out of film before we even go hiking, Ran-neechan.
سينفد الفيلم قبل أن نصعد الجبل حتّى يا ران-نيتشان
We'll be fine! Here, let's get one together!
!لا تقلق، لنأخذ صورة معاً
Hey, Dad! Take our picture!
!التقط صورتنا يا أبي
Ugh! We're not here for fun, you know!
!يا إلهي! لم نأت هنا للهو
Here, Dad!
هاك يا أبي
You guys understand, right?!
أنتما! تفهمان ما نفعله، صحيح؟
Of course! We're here to make it look like you're an ordinary hiker!
بالطبع! أتينا لجعلك تبدو متسلّق جبليّ عاديّ
Which means we'll seem suspicious if we don't take pictures!
مما يعني أنّنا سنبدو مريبين إذا لم نلتقط صوراً
Oh, right.
فهمت
Oh, man...
...أنت
Shortly after, we filled out the hiking forms at the office
بعد ذلك، ملأنا استمارات التسلّق الجبلي
at the base of the mountain.
في المكتب في سفح الجبل
They faxed the number of hikers and their names to a mountain lodge
أرسلوا أرقام وأسماء المتنزهين بالفاكس إلى كوخ جبليّ
so they could prepare our meals and such before we stayed the night.
كي يحضّروا وجباتنا وما إلى ذلك قبل أن نبيت هناك
Let's see... Here we go, the mountain lodge.
!إذاً... ها هو، الكوخ الجبليّ
We're staying the night here.
سنبيت هنا
It's a route for experts, so you better be ready!
!إنّه مسار للخبراء، فعليك التحضّر
You too, Ran-neechan!
أنتِ أيضاً يا ران-نيتشان
Oh, what's with that tone?
ما نبرتك هذه؟
Hey there! Is this your first time?
مرحباً! أهذه أوّل مرة لكم؟
I'm Hirai. I'm in my college's hiking club.
اسمي هيراي، أنا عضوٌ في نادي صعود الجبال في جامعتي
Hirai Kenichi (22) Toto Univ. Hiking Club
(22) هيراي كينيتشي نادي صعود الجبال لجامعة توتو
I come here every year.
آتي هنا كلّ عام
So you can count on me!
فيمكنكم الاعتماد عليّ
Great! We appreciate the help!
!حسناً! شكراً جزيلاً
Hey, now. He could be the Fox, you know!
...مهلك، قد يكون الثعلب
I'm Ran! Oh, and this is my little brother, Conan!
!اسمي ران! وهذا أخي الصغير كونان
Oh, uhh...
...حسناً
And this is my father!
وهذا أبي
I'm from Tokyo. My name's Mori--
...أنا من طوكيو، اسمي موري
Moriyama!
!أقصد مورياما
I'm Ushio, from Kansai! Good to know you!
أنا أوشيو من كانساي! هلّا أضفتموني معكم؟
Nice to meet you!
!سُررنا بلقائك
Well then, let's all go cheerily!
!لنكن على وفاق جميعاً إذاً
I work for a real estate agency. How about you?
أعمل لوكالة عقارات، ماذا عنك؟
Takanashi Wataru (50) Company Exec
ما-ما أهميّة ذلك؟
W-What does it matter?!
(50) تاكاناشي واتارو إداريّ في شركة
Given these clouds, the weather might change.
بالنظر لهذه الغيوم، قد يتغيّر الطقس
I'll give the mountain lodge a call.
سأتّصل بالكوخ الجبليّ
Does he have a thing for you?!
أهو مهتمٌ بك؟
The Fox is apparently left-handed.
الثعلب أعسر وفقما يبدو
He's thrown all his knives with his left hand.
رمى كلّ سكاكينه بيده اليسرى
Take a look at that man there.
انظر لذاك الرجل
He's left-handed!
!إنّه أيسر
So he is!
!بالفعل
Oh, Gramps? This is Hirai. I'll be staying again tonight!
الجدّ؟ أنا هيراي، سأبيت الليلة أيضاً
Umm, Moriyama-san, was it? Have we met somewhere before?
المعذرة، كان اسمك مورياما-سان؟ هل التقينا قبلاً؟
Nose Shingo (35) Novelist
أنا نوسي شينغو، روائيّ
I'm Nose Shingo. I write novels.
(35) نوسي شينغو روائيّ
Oh, the Nose Shingo-san who wrote The Beautiful Amnesiac Case?!
أيمكن أنّك نوسي شينغو-سان الذي ألّف "قضيّة لغز الحسناء فاقدة الذاكرة"؟
Oh, wow! I'm so happy to meet one of my very few readers!
!يسرّني لقاء أحد قرّائي المعدودين
You read it too, didn't you, Conan-kun?
قرأتها أيضاً يا كونان-كن، صحيح؟
Y-Yeah.
أجل
It was about a killer with amnesia, if I'm not mistaken.
كانت عن قاتلة فقدت ذاكرتها وفقما أذكر
I recall the trick being pretty lame...
...كانت الحيلة سخيفة
We haven't missed the check-in time, have we?!
!لم يفتنا التسجيل بعد، صحيح؟
Please add us to the list, too!
!لتضفنا أيضاً رجاءً
Looks like it's gonna be a pretty big group...
يبدو أنّها ستكون مجموعة كبيرة
We don't know the way,
لا نعرف الطريق
Saegusa Kyoko (25) Hiker
(سايغوسا كيوكو (25 متسلقة جبلية
so I hope you don't mind us coming along.
فأرجو ألّا تمانعوا اصطحابنا
No, not at all!
أهلاً بكما
Come to think of it, we don't know the Fox's gender for sure.
بالمناسبة، لا نعرف جنس الثعلب
It could be a woman!
قد يكون امرأة
Sorry to keep you waiting! I'm Kawabe! It's nice to meet you!
!نعتذر على الإطالة، أنا كاوابي يسرّنا لقاؤكما
And so the traverse began.
وهكذا بدأ تسلّق الجبال
Assuming the Fox is going to strike in this limited time and space,
بافتراض أنّ الثعلب سيهاجم في هذا النطاق الزمنيّ والمكانيّ المحدودين
he's either waiting in the mountains for his chance, like a guerilla,
فإمّا أنّه يختبئ في الجبال منتظراً فرصته ،كرجل عصابة
or he's one of the hikers.
أو أنّه أحد المتسلّقين
In short, there's a good chance one of the other five people is the Fox!
أي أنّ هناك احتمالاً كبيراً أن يكون الثعلب أحد الخمسة الآخرين
Be careful, it's slippery here!
توخّوا الحذر، الصخور زلقة
There you go.
لا عليك، هيّا
Please hold onto the rope.
تمسّكوا بالحبل رجاءً
Watch out!
!انتبه
Are you all right, Ushio-san?!
أأنت بخير يا أوشيو-سان؟
How dare you...
...كيف تجرؤ
W-What are you doing?!
ما-ما الذي تفعله؟
You did that on purpose!
!أنت من فعل ذلك، صحيح؟
No! This snapped on its own! See!
كلا، انقطع من تلقاء نفسه! انظر
It was all old and worn out.
كان قديماً وبالياً
Don't scare me like that!
لا تخفني هكذا
T-That's my line!
!هـ-هذه جملتي
When I consider the Fox being one of the traverse members...
عندما أفكّر بكون الثعلب ،أحد مجموعة المتسلّقين
...everyone seems a likely suspect!
يصبح الجميع مثيرين للشبهة
Those two really seem suspicious.
يبدوان مشبوهين
Him, too.
وهو أيضاً
He's been glaring like crazy this whole time.
كان يحدّق بشدة لفترة
He looks like he has something against Ushio-san.
يبدو أنّه يكنّ ضغينةً ما لأوشيو-سان
Plus he was way ahead before, but now he's with us...
كما كان يسبقنا بكثير، لكنّه معنا الآن
Hey, you two.
أنتما
Whatcha talkin' about? Are you people-watching?
ما الذي تتكلمان عنه؟ أتقومان بمراقبة الآخرين؟
N-No, we're just...
...لـ-لا، كنّا فقط
Nothing happened after that,
لم يحصل شيء بعدها
as we approached the final rest spot before our lodging for the night.
بينما اقتربنا من نقطة الارتياح الأخيرة قبل الوصول للكوخ الذي سنبيت فيه
What?
ماذا؟
Nothing... You just seem full of energy...
لا شيء... تبدين مفعمة بالحيويّة فحسب
Of course I am! I'm in shape because of my karate training!
!بالطبع! فأنا أمرّن جسدي بالكاراتيه
Want to try out a leg technique?
أتريد تلقّي إحدى تقنيات ساقي؟
No, that's okay.
لا داعي
Say, where's that college guy?
أين ذاك الشاب الجامعيّ؟
Probably taking a rest somewhere.
لعلّه يستريح في مكانٍ ما
Or he ran off 'cause his cover got blown!
!أو هرب لأنّ حقيقته كُشفت
Shh! Ushio-san!
!صه! أوشيو-سان
They said the cover's been blown!
!قالوا أنّ حقيقته كُشفت وهرب
Keep quiet! Let's go!
!اصمتي! هيّا بنا
There seems to be something to those two...
...هناك أمرٌ ما بهذين الاثنين
H-Help! Someone!
!مـ-مشكلة! ليأت أحد
Hurry! Someone!
!بسرعة! ليأت أحد
What's going on?!
!ما الخطب؟
D-Down there!
!ذ-ذاك
Down there...
...ذاك
Hirai-san!
!هيراي-سان
W-Why?!
!لـ-لمَ؟
Why? Why Hirai-san...
...لمَ؟ لمَ هيراي-سان
So it wasn't him?
لم يكن هو إذاً؟
You did this!
!أنت من فعل هذا
You threw him over, didn't you?!
!قمت بدفعه، أليس كذلك؟
L-Let go! Don't touch me!
!د-دعني! لا تلمسني
Stop!
!توقّف
Shouldn't we hurry down there and take a look?
ألا يجدر بنا الإسراع وتفقّد الجثّة؟
Oh, right!
...صحيح
Poor guy...
الرجل المسكين
He had to have died instantly...
لا بدّ أنّه مات فورياً
Hey, you. Don't be wandering around. It's dangerous.
!أنت، لا تتجوّل في المكان !هذا خطر
A knife! There's a little blood on it!
!إنّها سكّين! عليها دم قليل
What?! A knife?! D-Don't tell me the Fox did this!
...ماذا؟ سكّين؟ أيمكن أنّ الثعلب قد
But he doesn't have any stab marks...
لكن لا آثار طعن عليه
This mark!
...هذا الجرح
Ah!
فهمت
Look! This cut looks like the knife grazed him!
!انظر! يبدو أنّ هذا أثر خدشه بالسكّين
And the fact that the knife is lying there...
...وكون السكّين ملقاة هنا
...means he dodged a knife the killer threw...
...يعني أنّه تفادى السكّين التي رماها الفاعل
...but he lost his footing and fell off the cliff...
...لكنه تعثر
So he intended to kill him?
نوى قتله إذاً؟
You! Where've you been?!
!أنت! أين كنت؟
I've been around.
في الأرجاء
The hell you have!
!كاذب
I went on ahead, but came back when I heard screaming.
كنتُ أمامكم، لكن رجعت بعدما سمعت صراخاً
I mean, those guys seem pretty fishy if you ask me...
انظر، مع هذين الاثنين المريبين
What?! Them?!
ماذا؟ هما؟
Screw this! These people are nothing but trouble!
لا تمازحونا! مرافقة هؤلاء الأشخاص !لن تجلب سوى المتاعب
Let's get going!
لنذهب بسرعة
Hold it! We're all going to wait at the mountain lodge!
!لحظة! سننتظر جميعاً في الكوخ الجبليّ
I must ask you all to stay with us until the police arrive.
سأطلب منكما البقاء معنا حتّى وصول الشرطة
Screw that! W-What gives you the right to do that?!
!لا تعبث معنا! أ-أيّ حق لديك لتطلب ذلك؟
Whoever leaves a murder scene will seem all the more suspicious.
أيّ من يغادر مسرح جريمة قتل سيُشتبه به
Damn!
!تبّاً
Moriyama-san. You seem quite accustomed to this. What's your job?
تبدو معتاداً كثيراً على هذا يا مورياما-سان، ما عملك؟
Oh, I, uh...
...أنا
He's an office worker! Right, Dad?
موظّف شركة! صحيح يا أبي؟
Y-Yeah, that's right!
!نـ-نعم
An office worker, huh?
موظّف شركة إذاً؟
He definitely doesn't look like it...
لا يبدو عليه البتّة
Rain!
!مطر
Let's hurry!
!لنسرع
Iwata Jukichi (60) Cabin Manager
جفّفوا أنفسكم، ستلوّثون الكوخ
Dry yourselves off. You'll filthy up the cabin.
(إيواتا جوكيتشي (60 مشرف الكوخ
Are you the manager of this cabin, old man?
أأنت المشرف على هذا الكوخ يا جدّ؟
Yes. Come inside, already! You'll catch cold!
!نعم، فلتدخلوا بسرعة! سيصيبكم الزكام
Whew...
...يا إلهي
I'm exhausted...
أشعر بالإرهاق
Dad. Aren't you going to call?
أبي، ألن تتّصل؟
Oh, right.
صحيح
I'm gonna use the phone, mister.
سأستعمل الهاتف يا جدّ
What the-- I'm not even getting a tone! Umm--
...ما هذا؟ لا أسمع طنيناً، المعذرة
The lines probably got knocked out during all that lightning earlier...
قُطعت خطوط الهاتف مع الصاعقة قبل قليل غالباً
Happens all the time.
هذا شائع الحدوث
Now, what? It's raining, it's night...
...يا للمشكلة، إنّها تمطر وحلّ الليل
It's dangerous to go down mountains at night! I'd advise against it!
!من الخطر النزول من الجبال ليلاً !أنصحكم ألّا تفعلوا
Not to mention this is the summit. There are no other cabins nearby.
كما أنّ هذه قمّة تانبارا، لا أكواخ أخرى بالقرب
Meaning we're pretty much completely isolated.
أي أنّنا معزولون تماماً
You can't be serious!
!لا يمكن
What the hell?! I can't believe we're trapped in here with a murderer!
لا تمازحونا! لا أصدّق أنّنا !عالقون هنا مع قاتل
Murderer?
قاتل؟
One of our companions was murdered in a fake accident.
قُتل أحد أعضاء المجموعة بشكل يوهم أنّه كان حادثاً
A fake accident?
يوهم أنّه حادث؟
Tarnishing these mountains like that... how shameful!
لكن، كيف يلطّخ الجبال بهذا الشكل؟ يا للخزي
Anyway, the killer could be in this very room.
قد يكون القاتل أحدنا
Who knows? Maybe it was you, Ushio-san.
من يدري، لعلّه أنت يا أوشيو-سان
S-Say what?!
!مـ-ماذا؟
It's common sense in mysteries that the killer is the least likely person.
من المنطقي في روايات الغموض أنّ القاتل هو الأقلّ شبهة
Rubbish! I'm starving! Food!
!هراء! أنا أتضوّر جوعاً، الطعام
Curry Rice
كاري أرز
This... is dinner?
هذا هو العشاء؟
What do you want? We're in the mountains.
نحن في الجبال، ماذا تتوقّعون؟
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Oh, nothing.
...لا شيء
What is this feeling of strangeness?
ما شعور الغرابة هذا؟
Something's not right!
!هناك أمرٌ ليس في محلّه
What could it be?!
ما هو؟
What do you think's wrong with Takanashi-san?
ما خطب تاكاناشي-سان يا ترى؟
He knows what he's done.
لعلّ ضميره يؤنبه
You really did...
...كنتَ إذاً من
N-No!
!كـ-كلا
D-Don't kill us!
!لا-لا تقتلنا
What nonsense! Everyone carries hunting knives when hiking!
سخافة! يحمل الجميع سكاكين !صيد عند صعود الجبال
T-That's true, but...
...ذ-ذلك صحيح، لكن
I remember now! Moriyama-san!
...تذكّرت! مورياما-سان، أنت
You're Mori Kogoro-san, the great detective, aren't you?!
موري كوغورو-سان، صحيح؟ المتحرّي الشهير
D-Detective?!
مـ-متحرّي؟
D-Don't tell me...
...أيمكن
What's with the false name? Are you on some sorta case?
لمَ زيّفت اسمك؟ أهناك قضيّة ما؟
Personal reasons? Or... could it have to do with this murder?
...أم أسباب خاصة؟ أم للأمر علاقة بجريمة القتل هذه؟
Sheesh! How long is it going to rain?
يا إلهي! إلى متى ستظلّ تمطر؟
What's the forecast got in store?
ما هي نشرة الطقس؟
You can tell me in secret. C'mon.
يمكنك إخباري سرّاً، هيّا
Now for the next news item.
ننتقل للأنباء التالية
This morning, Tanaka Yoro, 60, was fatally stabbed in Tanbara Village,
،طُعن هذا الصباح تاناكا يورو، 60 عاماً بطعنة مميتة في قرية تانبارا
and the suspects may have fled into the Tanbara Mountains.
وهناك احتمال بهروب المشتبه به لجبال تانبارا
Police and fire departments have a 50-man team searching the area.
أرسلت الشرطة 50 رجلاً مع مركز الإطفاء لتفتيش المنطقة
Oh, come on! I can't sleep like this!
!لن يغمض لي جفن هكذا
Look out!
!انتبه
What the--?!
ما هذا؟
Dad?!
!أبي؟
Someone just left!
!غادر أحدهم
What's going on?
ما الأمر؟
Takanashi-san is gone!
!تاكاناشي-سان ليس موجوداً
I knew it was him!
!كان هو بالفعل إذاً
Damn you! You can't get away from us!
!الوغد! لن تهرب
Be careful! You're the one he's after!
!توخَّ الحذر! فأنت هدفه
Let's go!
!حسنٌ
Takanashi-san!
تاكاناشي-سان؟
What was that?
ما كان ذلك؟
Help! Help me!
!النجدة! النجدة
H-H-Help!
!الـ-النجدة
H-Help me!
!النجدة
Watch out, Conan!
!انتبه يا كونان
It's the Fox!
!الثعلب
Wait! Something's not right!
!انتظر! حاله غريب
T-The ceiling's falling!
!الـ-السقف يسقط
The walls are closing in! I'm scared! I'm scared!
!الـ-الحوائط تُطبِق عليّ! أشعر بالخوف! أشعر بالخوف
Help me!
!النجدة
H-Huh?
ما-ماذا؟
I think he might have claustrophobia.
لعلّه يعاني رهاباً من الأماكن الضيّقة
Claustrophobia?
رهاب أماكن ضيّقة؟
Meaning that's why he rushed out of the cabin?
ولذلك هرب من الكوخ؟
Yeah. And he came here to avoid the rain, but then it happened again.
أجل، ثمّ دخل هنا للاحتماء من المطر لكن رجعت حالته
Which means he's...
...أي أنّه
...not the Fox...
لم يكن الثعلب
Some land sharks once held me captive.
احتجزني مشترو أراضٍ مرّةً
I got them mad when I refused to sell my land.
أغضبتُهم بعدما رفضت بيع أرضي
I've been afraid of cramped places ever since...
وأصبحتُ أخشى الأماكن الضيّقة مُذ آنذاك
So that's also why you don't like the real estate guy!
لذا كنت لا تطيق مسؤول العقارات
Good call, kid.
تخمينٌ موفق يا فتى
But that means the Fox is still on the loose!
!لكن ذلك يعني أنّ الثعلب لا يزال طليقاً
Which one of the other four is the hitman?!
من بين الأربعة المتبقّين، من هو القاتل المأجور؟
That was Ran!
!صوت ران
D-Don't tell me something's happened to Ran?!
!أ-أيمكن أن أمراً حلّ بران؟
The Fox is in this room. And he's the one behind these murders!
الثعلب موجود هنا، وهو من يقف وراء !سلسلة جرائم القتل هذه
The hitman?!
ذاك القاتل المأجور؟
The Fox?!
!الثعلب؟
Yes! The peerless hitman, the Fox, the one behind these incidents...
أجل! القاتل المأجور بلا نظير ،والمسؤول عن هذه الجرائم، أي الثعلب
...is you, the novelist, Nose Shingo!
!هو أنت أيّها الروائيّ، نوسي شينغو
R-Really?!
!حـ-حقّاً؟
Damn you!
!أيّها الوغد
W-What are you doing?!
!ما-ما الذي تفعله؟
On the next Conan: "The Traverse of Terror Murder Case (Part 2)."
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Mountain lodge record notebook.
سجّل كوخ جبلي